<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>RC - Tag - Yuri's Car Factory</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/tags/rc/</link><description>RC - Tag - Yuri's Car Factory</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 17:00:59 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/tags/rc/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Classic Land Rover Defender, v1 (with 4L motors and RC electronics)</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/defender-110/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 17:00:59 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/defender-110/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I didn&rsquo;t originally plan to build a Land Rover Defender model. My idea was to build a chassis with a 2-speed gearbox, locking center and rear differentials, suitable for an off-road vehicle. Something similar to my <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v04/" rel="">Unimog</a>, but a car, not a truck. And once the chassis is ready, I would only need to find a suitable body.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>42043 Arocs (2L motors, RC electronics)</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42043-b-arocs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 05:00:32 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42043-b-arocs/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my motorized version of the &lt;a href="https://rebrickable.com/sets/42043-1-b1/mercedes-benz-arocs-1845-articulated-construction-truck/?inventory=2#parts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">LEGO 42043-1-b1 Mercedes-Benz Arocs&lt;/a> set. My goal was to keep all the features of the original model, its exterior and interior and, at the same time, make the model nice to play with.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wrangler Rubicon, v2 (with 4L motors and RC electronics)</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 17:00:59 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is the second version of my Wrangler Jeep. The <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v01/" rel="">previous one</a> was built with Power Functions, had 2 L-motors and a gearbox. In the new version I decided to focus on power and playability so I put 4 L-motors for driving and used RC electronics to get proportional steering and driving. The 4 L-motors layout idea was inspired by the <a href="https://www.eurobricks.com/forum/index.php?/forums/topic/188469-moc-jeep-wrangler/&amp;tab=comments#comment-3471625" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Jeep Wrangler</a> model by Daniel-99.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Setting up 4WS (4 wheels steering) on FlySky GT3C with alternative firmware</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/flysky-gt3c-crab-config/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 23:59:59 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/flysky-gt3c-crab-config/</guid><description>In this video I show how to setup 4 wheels steering (4WS) and switching between front / full / rear steering modes on a FlySky GT3C radio with alternative firmware.
Practical use Resources Alternative firmware for FlySky FS-GT3B/C</description></item><item><title>Der Unimog - 8110 MOD v4 (with 4L motors and RC electronics)</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v04/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 05:00:32 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v04/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is the fourth version of my trial truck built from the LEGO <a href="https://rebrickable.com/sets/8110-1/unimog-u400/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">8110 Unimog U400</a> set. This time, I decided to use RC components instead of the LEGO PF-compatible system to get proportional steering and driving. The truck also features a two-speed gearbox with a center differential that automatically locks in low gear. The gearbox layout is similar to the <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-v04/" rel="">Land Rover Defender v4</a>, so the ratios are the same - 1:1 in hi gear and 1.67:1 in low gear. The truck is powered by four PF-compatible motors that provide decent speed and torque. For steering, I used a Geek Servo motor, and another Geek Servo motor is used for shifting the gearbox.
The model is powered by a 3S LiPo battery (3x18650) which is located above the rear axle for better weight distribution.</p>
<p>The chassis dimensions are the same as the original <a href="https://rebrickable.com/sets/8110-1/unimog-u400/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">8110 Unimog U400</a> set. Instead of the fake engine, an L-motor is installed for the front PTO.</p>
<p>The cabin is almost the same as in the <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v03/" rel="">previous version</a>, only the passenger seat became wider.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>