<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Wrangler - Tag - Yuri's Car Factory</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/tags/wrangler/</link><description>Wrangler - Tag - Yuri's Car Factory</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 17:00:59 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/tags/wrangler/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wrangler Rubicon, v2 (with 4L motors and RC electronics)</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 17:00:59 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is the second version of my Wrangler Jeep. The <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v01/" rel="">previous one</a> was built with Power Functions, had 2 L-motors and a gearbox. In the new version I decided to focus on power and playability so I put 4 L-motors for driving and used RC electronics to get proportional steering and driving. The 4 L-motors layout idea was inspired by the <a href="https://www.eurobricks.com/forum/index.php?/forums/topic/188469-moc-jeep-wrangler/&amp;tab=comments#comment-3471625" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Jeep Wrangler</a> model by Daniel-99.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Wrangler Rubicon, v1</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 23:59:59 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v01/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>After finishing the <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-v04/" rel="">42110 Land Rover Defender, v4</a>, I decided to build a classic Wrangler Jeep Rubicon which would be lighter and more off-road capable.</p>
<p>This model is based on and inspired by two great models: <a href="https://rebrickable.com/mocs/MOC-30015/Sheepo/jeep-wrangler-rubicon-manual-version/#details" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">MOC - Jeep Wrangler Rubicon</a> by Sheepo and <a href="https://rebrickable.com/mocs/MOC-92929/gyenesvi/42129-c-model-jeep-wrangler/#details" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">MOC - 42129 C model - Jeep Wrangler</a> by Viktor Gyenes.</p>
<p>I opted for the black and yellow color scheme, but since some of the original parts do not exist in yellow or black, I decided to use non-original ones. I also used black 3L pins instead of blue ones in all visible places. The model got 85x28mm RC tyres on black rims.<br>
I tried to make both interior and exterior interesting, but at the same time not so detailed to keep the model not heavy. The curb weight of the model is 1.63 kg, which is almost 400 grams less than the <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-v04/" rel="">42110 Land Rover Defender, v4</a>.</p>
<p>I used non-original PF receivers operating at 2.4 GHz, which allowed them to be completely hidden under the hood. The LiPo battery is located behind the seats.</p>
<p>The gearbox and both differentials are protected by panels.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>