<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Video - Tag - Yuri's Car Factory</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/tags/video/</link><description>Video - Tag - Yuri's Car Factory</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 17:00:59 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/tags/video/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nordic — DIY Wooden Tugboat Model (Part 1)</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/nordic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 17:00:59 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/nordic/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my first attempt at building a wooden RC model ship. The plans were published in the Polish magazine “Modelarz” #6 1969 - “Holownik Klimek”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Classic Land Rover Defender, v1 (with 4L motors and RC electronics)</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/defender-110/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 17:00:59 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/defender-110/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I didn&rsquo;t originally plan to build a Land Rover Defender model. My idea was to build a chassis with a 2-speed gearbox, locking center and rear differentials, suitable for an off-road vehicle. Something similar to my <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v04/" rel="">Unimog</a>, but a car, not a truck. And once the chassis is ready, I would only need to find a suitable body.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Wrangler Rubicon, v2 (with 4L motors and RC electronics)</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 17:00:59 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is the second version of my Wrangler Jeep. The <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v01/" rel="">previous one</a> was built with Power Functions, had 2 L-motors and a gearbox. In the new version I decided to focus on power and playability so I put 4 L-motors for driving and used RC electronics to get proportional steering and driving. The 4 L-motors layout idea was inspired by the <a href="https://www.eurobricks.com/forum/index.php?/forums/topic/188469-moc-jeep-wrangler/&amp;tab=comments#comment-3471625" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Jeep Wrangler</a> model by Daniel-99.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Setting up 4WS (4 wheels steering) on FlySky GT3C with alternative firmware</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/flysky-gt3c-crab-config/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 23:59:59 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/flysky-gt3c-crab-config/</guid><description>In this video I show how to setup 4 wheels steering (4WS) and switching between front / full / rear steering modes on a FlySky GT3C radio with alternative firmware.
Practical use Resources Alternative firmware for FlySky FS-GT3B/C</description></item><item><title>Der Unimog - 8110 MOD v4 (with 4L motors and RC electronics)</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v04/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 05:00:32 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v04/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is the fourth version of my trial truck built from the LEGO <a href="https://rebrickable.com/sets/8110-1/unimog-u400/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">8110 Unimog U400</a> set. This time, I decided to use RC components instead of the LEGO PF-compatible system to get proportional steering and driving. The truck also features a two-speed gearbox with a center differential that automatically locks in low gear. The gearbox layout is similar to the <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-v04/" rel="">Land Rover Defender v4</a>, so the ratios are the same - 1:1 in hi gear and 1.67:1 in low gear. The truck is powered by four PF-compatible motors that provide decent speed and torque. For steering, I used a Geek Servo motor, and another Geek Servo motor is used for shifting the gearbox.
The model is powered by a 3S LiPo battery (3x18650) which is located above the rear axle for better weight distribution.</p>
<p>The chassis dimensions are the same as the original <a href="https://rebrickable.com/sets/8110-1/unimog-u400/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">8110 Unimog U400</a> set. Instead of the fake engine, an L-motor is installed for the front PTO.</p>
<p>The cabin is almost the same as in the <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v03/" rel="">previous version</a>, only the passenger seat became wider.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>42082 Rough Terrain Crane Full RC MOD</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42082-red-crane-v01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 06:00:19 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42082-red-crane-v01/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is my MOD of the official <a href="https://rebrickable.com/sets/42082-1/rough-terrain-crane/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">42082</a> set. Like many others, I wasn&rsquo;t happy with the playability of the original set, so I decided to improve it.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Wrangler Rubicon, v1</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 23:59:59 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/wrangler-v01/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>After finishing the <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-v04/" rel="">42110 Land Rover Defender, v4</a>, I decided to build a classic Wrangler Jeep Rubicon which would be lighter and more off-road capable.</p>
<p>This model is based on and inspired by two great models: <a href="https://rebrickable.com/mocs/MOC-30015/Sheepo/jeep-wrangler-rubicon-manual-version/#details" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">MOC - Jeep Wrangler Rubicon</a> by Sheepo and <a href="https://rebrickable.com/mocs/MOC-92929/gyenesvi/42129-c-model-jeep-wrangler/#details" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">MOC - 42129 C model - Jeep Wrangler</a> by Viktor Gyenes.</p>
<p>I opted for the black and yellow color scheme, but since some of the original parts do not exist in yellow or black, I decided to use non-original ones. I also used black 3L pins instead of blue ones in all visible places. The model got 85x28mm RC tyres on black rims.<br>
I tried to make both interior and exterior interesting, but at the same time not so detailed to keep the model not heavy. The curb weight of the model is 1.63 kg, which is almost 400 grams less than the <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-v04/" rel="">42110 Land Rover Defender, v4</a>.</p>
<p>I used non-original PF receivers operating at 2.4 GHz, which allowed them to be completely hidden under the hood. The LiPo battery is located behind the seats.</p>
<p>The gearbox and both differentials are protected by panels.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>8110 Unimog MOD v3 - Orange trial truck</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 05:00:32 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v03/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is the third (and final, for now) version of my trial truck built from the LEGO <a href="https://rebrickable.com/sets/8110-1/unimog-u400/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">8110 Unimog U400</a> set. In this version, I managed to fix some issues with the chassis and improve the overall appearance. Thanks to <a href="https://rebrickable.com/parts/92908/technic-steering-portal-axle-housing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">portal hubs</a> and new differentials, the truck is powerful enough, but at the same time it&rsquo;s not a crawler, it&rsquo;s fun to play with both inside and outside.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>42110 Land Rover Defender, v4</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-v04/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 23:59:59 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-v04/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is the final version of my motorized Land Rover Defender 42110, featuring the <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-chassis-v03/" rel="">v3 chassis</a>. Instead of the original Land Rover Defender body, I opted for a lighter and more attractive design. I came across an excellent <a href="https://rebrickable.com/mocs/MOC-35068" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">MOC-35068</a> on Rebrickable which I based my solution on. I sacrificed the back door for the strength of the body.</p>
<p>I really like the resulting model, it has excellent playability. Thanks to the two-speed RC gearbox, it can move quickly on high gear and easily overcome obstacles on low gear. <a href="https://rebrickable.com/parts/46490/wheel-hub-with-planetary-gear-reduction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Wheel hubs with planetary gear reduction</a> provide excellent &ldquo;off-road&rdquo; capability, and the car&rsquo;s weight balance makes it easy to climb 40-degree slopes. The weak point of the chassis - a protruding 16-tooth gear - is covered with an overlay made of curved slopes that protects the gear when passing obstacles. The center differential enables smooth turns, while the robust chassis and gearbox prevent gear slipping and crunching when driving over obstacles. Additionally, the RC winch is powerful enough to pull the model.</p>
<p>The LED headlights look very natural, there are no visible wires on the outside.
When they&rsquo;re turned off, they&rsquo;re almost indistinguishable from the headlights on the original model. Both the headlights and the taillights are bright enough for driving in the dark.</p>
<p>The model also looks great on the shelf. I used non-original PF receivers operating at 2.4 GHz, which allowed them to be completely hidden inside the body. The LiPo battery is also hidden inside. The power switch is located inside the decorative gray trunk. I used black 3L pins instead of blue ones in all visible places and covered the holes in the technic beams with system tiles.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>