<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>WIP - Tag - Yuri's Car Factory</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/tags/wip/</link><description>WIP - Tag - Yuri's Car Factory</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 01:21:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/tags/wip/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>8110 Unimog MOD, v2</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v02/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 01:21:32 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v02/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>The first version of the <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/8110-unimog-v01/" rel="">Unimog 8110</a> was staying on the shelf for almost a year before I decided to improve it.</p>
<p>The front and rear axles remain the same. I added a second XL motor for driving and connected them both to the center differential. Unlike the original set, I decided to use a <a href="https://rebrickable.com/parts/62821b/technic-gear-differential-with-inner-tabs-and-closed-center-28-bevel-teeth-beveled-edge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">28 bevel tooth differential</a> here. The reason for this decision is the easier placement and connection of the XL motors.</p>
<p>I took non-original XL motors, which have higher RPM than the original ones, to achieve higher speed.  The truck also got a center differential lock activated by a CaDA micromotor.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the center differential turned out to be a weak point. Due to the lack of support, it sometimes made a crackling sound under load, especially when changing driving direction. A possible solution I thought of is to add two beams on the left and right instead of 14 tooth gears. But in this case, I would have lost the ability to lock the differential, which is necessary for the trial truck.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>42110 Land Rover Defender chassis, v3</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-chassis-v03/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 19:45:47 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-chassis-v03/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>The third version of the Land Rover Defender chassis. To date, this is the most successful version. All functions work well, the gearbox does not slip even under load. The connection between the servo motor and the steering rack is half that of the previous version, resulting in less steering play. Let&rsquo;s see how the chassis will behave after adding the Land Rover&rsquo;s massive body!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>42110 Land Rover Defender chassis, v2</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-chassis-v02/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 10:12:47 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-chassis-v02/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is the second version of the Land Rover Defender chassis. Compared to the <a href="https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-chassis-v03/" rel="">first version</a>, it now features Ackermann steering and some changes were made to the gearbox and transmission.</p>
<p>Despite all efforts, the design of the gearbox and transmission turned out to be not reliable enough; when passing over obstacles (even in low gear), it sometimes made a crackling noise. The weight balance was also far from ideal - the rear part of the chassis was heavier than the front. After adding a body, the weight balance would shifted back even more. The steering mechanism also needs to be improved - it has too much play</p>
<p>It was a good start, but I decided to take this chassis apart and look for a better solution.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>42110 Land Rover Defender chassis, v1</title><link>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-chassis-v01/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 17:10:47 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://orangetrialtruck.nl/posts/42110-landrover-chassis-v01/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is my first attempt at motorizing the LEGO <a href="https://rebrickable.com/sets/42110-1/land-rover-defender/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">42110 Land Rover Defender</a> set. It features two PF L motors for driving and a servo motor for steering. I used non-original motors, which have higher RPM than the original ones, to achieve higher speed. The center differential is absent. The two-speed gearbox is shifted by a CaDA micro motor.</p>
<p>All functions work fine, but I&rsquo;m disappointed with the performance and reliability of this version - the gears sometimes slip and crunch when driving over obstacles. Also, there is too much play in the steering mechanism.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>